Finding Aid for the Stella and William Vaughn Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Stella and William Vaughn Collection
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0477
9.24 linear_feet
- Series I: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbooks, 1877 – 1909 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1895 – 1950 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1910 – 1937 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks, 1910 – 1955 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbooks, 1917 – 1957 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1932 – 1946 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1944 – 1950 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1950 – 1953 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1954 – 1957 (Box 9)
- Series 2: Ornithology Papers
  - Audubon Societies (Box 10)
  - Brochures (Box 10)
  - Census and Field Days (Box 10)
  - Clippings (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (Box 10)
  - Field Notes (Box 10)
  - Maps (Box 10)
  - Notes (Box 10)
  - Resources and Tips (Box 10)
  - Tennessee Ornithological Society (Box 10)
  - Writings by Harry S. Vaughn (Box 11)
  - Illustrations (Box 11)
  - Nest Records (Box 11)
  - Notebook on Bird Nesting (Box 11)
  - Notebook on Birds in Agriculture (Box 11)
  - Notebook on Attributes of Birds (Box 11)
  - Notebooks on Birds (Box 11)
  - Believe It or Not of Birds (Box 11)
  - Writings, Misc. (Box 11)
- Series 3: Personal Papers
  - Letters from W. J. Vaughn (Box 12)
  - Letters to Harry S. Vaughn (Box 12)
  - Letters to Stella S. Vaughn (Box 12)
  - Letters to Mrs. Alice Hargrove Barclay (Box 12)
  - Letters to Mrs. W. J. Vaughn (Box 12)
  - Business Correspondence (Box 12)
  - Letters, Unidentified (Box 12)
  - Christmas Cards, 1920 (Box 12)
  - Letters, Unsorted (Box 12)
  - William J. Vaughn ledger books (Box 13)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta materials (Box 14)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta materials continued (Box 15)
  - Artifacts (Box 15)
  - Belmont Methodist Church (Box 15)
  - W. F. Bradshaw (Box 15)
  - Christian Advocate (magazine) (Box 15)
  - Historic Houses (Box 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 15)
  - Journal of Fannie A. Colton (Box 15)
  - J. H. Criddle (Box 15)
  - Mary Ann Davidson (Box 15)
  - John Fields (Box 15)
  - Financial Papers (Box 15)
  - Financial Papers continued (Box 16)
  - Florence Crittenton Mission Home (Box 16)
  - Robert H. Hargrove (Box 16)
  - Albert Mason Harris (Box 16)
  - History Notes (Box 16)
  - Illustrations (Box 16)
  - Lists (Box 16)
  - Music (Box 16)
  - Nashville Children’s Museum (Box 16)
  - Nashville, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Nashville Settlement House (Box 16)
  - Notes on Historic Houses (Box 16)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Notes on Nashville History (Box 16)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 17)
  - Phi Delta Theta (Box 17)
  - A. Ross Pittman (Box 17)
  - Poetry (Box 17)
  - Publications and notes (Box 17)
  - Publications – World Outlook (magazine) (Box 17)
  - Florence E. Sloan (Box 17)
  - Anna (DuPré) Smith (Box 17)
  - Ada Bell Stapleton (Box 17)
  - Taxidermy (Box 17)
  - Herbert Cushing Tolman (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Alumnae Council (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Alumni Memorial Hall (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Campus Maps (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Coeds (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Days by Stella Vaughn (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Joint University Libraries (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Kirkland Tower Bell (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Memorial Gym (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt newspaper clippings (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Programs and Brochures (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Publications (Box 17)
  - Vanderbilt Quinqs (Box 17)
  - Charles S. “Chile” Vaughn (Box 17)
  - Florence Vaughn (Box 17)
  - Harry S. Vaughn (Box 18)
  - Robert Hargrove Vaughn (Box 18)
  - Mrs. William J. Vaughn (Box 18)
  - Stella Scott Vaughn (Box 18)
  - W. S. Vaughn (Box 18)
  - Webb School (Box 18)
  - West End Methodist Church (Box 18)
  - H. W. Williams (Box 18)
  - Writings by Others (Box 18)
- Series 4: Photographs
  - Photograph Album (Box 19)
  - Photographs of People: (Box 20)
    - Negatives, unidentified (Box 20)
    - Amelia Baskervill (Box 20)
    - Children (Box 20)
    - Children’s Museum (Box 20)
    - Wallace Clark Collection (Children’s Museum) (Box 20)
    - Ann Davis (Box 20)
    - Faculty Children (Box 20)
    - Ella Ford (Box 20)
    - Griffin Family (Box 20)
    - Group Portraits (Box 20)
    - Katie Hargrove (Box 20)
    - Robert K. Hargrove (Box 20)
    - Houghlin Family (Box 20)
    - Lewis Family (Box 20)
    - Hallie Vaughn McConnell (Box 20)
    - J. T. McGill (Box 20)
    - E. D. and F. J. Patterson (Box 20)
    - Minnie Pearl (Children’s Museum) (Box 20)
    - Walter Raine (Box 20)
    - Robertson Academy, Class of, 1914 (Box 20)
    - Scott Family (Box 20)
    - Helen Todd Sloan (Box 20)
    - May A. Smith (Box 20)
    - Tennessee Ornithological Society Field Trip (Box 20)
    - John Paul Tyler (Box 20)
    - Unidentified People (Box 20)
    - Vanderbilt Engineering Hall, McTyeire Cornerstone Laying (Box 20)
    - Vanderbilt Graduation, 1905 (Box 20)
    - Vanderbilt Phi Delta Theta House (Box 20)
    - Vanderbilt Tennis Scenes (Box 20)
    - Abbie Scott Vaughn (Box 20)
    - Alex Barthell Vaughn (Box 20)
    - Harry S. Vaughn (Box 20)
    - Helen Vaughn (Box 20)
    - Stella Vaughn (Box 20)
    - William J. Vaughn (Box 20)
    - William S. Vaughn (Box 20)
    - Vaughn Family (Box 20)
    - W. D. Weatherford (Box 20)
  - Photographs of Places: (Box 20)
    - Ashland City (Box 20)
    - Austin Peay (Box 20)
    - Bear Hollow (Box 20)
    - Dickson (Box 20)
    - Edwin Warner Park (Box 20)
    - Henry Goodpasture Farm (Box 20)
    - Historic Buildings (Box 20)
    - Indian Lake (Box 20)
    - Lawrenceburg (Box 20)
    - Linden (Box 20)
  - Photographs of Places (Box 21)
    - Marribone (Box 21)
    - Nashville Children’s Museum (Box 21)
    - New Providence (Box 21)
    - Overshot Water Mills (North Carolina) (Box 21)
    - Postcards (Box 21)
    - Rail Fence (Box 21)
    - Rattlesnake Falls (Box 21)
    - State Teacher’s College, Murfreesboro, Tennessee (Box 21)
    - Sycamore Powder Mill (Box 21)
    - Tennessee Ornithological Society (Box 21)
    - Tuckaway Farm (Box 21)
    - Tuscaloosa, Alabama (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Coeds (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Dudley Field (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt, Miscellaneous (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Kappa Alpha Theta House (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Kirkland Hall (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Kirkland Hall Fire (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Residence Halls (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Residences (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Vaughn House (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Views (Box 21)
    - Vanderbilt Wesley Hall (Box 21)
    - Views, Unidentified (Box 21)
    - Wharton-Bullock Wreck (Box 21)
  - Aviation (Box 22)
  - China (Box 22)
  - Hankow (Box 22)
  - Mrs. R. D. Herbert (Box 22)
  - Printed Map of England (Box 22)
  - U.S.S. Houston (Box 22)
  - Vanderbilt Women’s Basketball Team Portraits, 1905, 1907 – 1908, 1910-1915 (Box 22)
  - Vanderbilt Women’s Gym Class, c 1895 (Box 22)
  - Vanderbilt Vaughn Residence (Box 22)
  - Charles S. Vaughn (Box 22)
  - Slides, Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Slides, Miscellaneous (Box 24)
- Series 5: Oversized Material
  - Harry S. and Stella Scott Vaughn Photo Album of Vanderbilt Scenes (Box 25)
  - Oversize Photographs (Box 26)
    - Aviation (Box 26)
    - Vanderbilt Campus Scenes (Box 26)
  - Scrapbook of lithographs cut from magazines, c1913 (Box 27)
  - Scrapbook of miscellaneous newspaper clippings, c1940s-1950s (Box 27)
  - General Contracting License for H. S. Vaughn (Box 28)
  - “Safe-a-Life” Campaign Flyer, March 25, 1930 (Box 28)
  - Vanderbilt Memorial Hall Flyer (Box 28)
  - Crimson White newspaper, University of Alabama, May 31, 1910 (Box 28)
  - Yankee Clipper Certificate (Box 28)
  - Theta Daily Kite, Kappa Alpha Theta newspaper, June 30, 1915, July 2, 1915 (Box 28)
  - Scrapbook, c1939 – 1954 (Box 28)
  - Scrapbook, undated, primarily pictures cut from magazines (Box 28)